Register of the Irwin T. and Shirley Holtzman collection, 1899-2010
Hoover Institution Archives
- Joseph Brodsky File, 1956-2000.
  - Printed matter. Publications by and about Joseph Brodsky, arranged chronologically. Hardback, unless otherwise indicated., See also Oversize file/Printed matter (Box 9)
    - Semicerchio, no. XII, 1995 (Box 16)
    - Sny: Poeticheskaia metafizika Peterburga, 1995 (Box 16)
    - Viereck, Peter, Tide and Continuities, 1995 (Box 16)
    - Volkov, Solomon, St. Petersburg: A Cultural History, 1995 (Box 16)
    - YevtushenkoBox Don't Die Before You're Dead, 1995 (Box 16)
    - The Georgia Review, Winter and Spring 1995 (Box 16)
    - The Harriman Review, July 1995 (Box 16)
    - Partisan Review, Summer 1995 (Box 16)
    - Agni, 1996 (Box 16)
    - Brodsky, Joseph, 1996 (Box 16)
      - On Grief and Reason (Box 16)
      - So Forth (Box 16)
    - Brodsky, Joseph et al., Homage to Robert Frost, 1996 (Box 16)
    - Dronnikov, N., Brodskii, 1996. (Box 16)
      Album of Dronnikov's drawings of Brodsky
    - Evrei v russkoi kul'ture za rubezhom, Vol. 5, 1996 (Box 16)
    - Fast, Piotr, Spotkania z Brodskim, 1996 (Box 16)
    - Hecht, Helen, Cuisine For All Seasons, 1996 (Box 16)
    - Kobak, A., Dom Muruzy, 1996 (Box 16)
    - Literaturnoe Obozrenie, no. 3, 1996 (Box 16)
    - Mitin Zhurnal, Dmitrii Volchek, ed., 1996 (Box 16)
    - Poetry in Motion, 1996 (Box 16)
    - Portfel': Literaturnyi sbornik, Aleksandr Sumerkin, ed., 1996 (Box 16)
    - This Prison Where I Live, Siobhan Dowd, ed., 1996 (Box 16)
    - Remnick, David, The Devil Problem and Other True Stories, 1996 (Box 16)
    - Zvezda, 1, 3, 5, 1996 (Box 16)
    - Poets and Writers, May/June 1996 (Box 16)
    - Modern Poetry in Translation, Winter 1996 (Box 16)
    - Batkin, Leonid, Tridtsat' tret'ia bukva, 1997 (Box 17)
    - Brodskii, Iosif, 1997 (Box 17)
      - Brodskii o Tsvetaevoi (Box 17)
      - Iosif Brodskii (Box 17)
      - Sochineniia Iosifa Brodskogo, t. I (Box 17)
    - Brodsky, Joseph, 1997 (Box 17)
      - First and Last Poems, A. Dickman, trans. In Hebrew (Box 17)
      - On Grief and Reason (Box 17)
    - Chukovskaia, Lidiia, Zapiski ob Anne Akhmatovoi, 1997 (Box 17)
    - The Pheonix Book Shop: A Nest of Memories, Bob Wilson et al., eds., 1997 (Box 17)
    - Poets: A Book of Postcards, 1997 (Box 17)
    - Rein, Evgenii, Mne skuchno bez Dovlatova, 1997 (Box 17)
    - Strizhevskaia, Natalia, Pismena perspektivy, 1997 (Box 17)
    - Venclova, Tomas, Winter Dialogue, 1997 (Box 17)
    - Zvezda, nos. 1 and 4, 1997 (Box 17)
    - Brodskii, Iosif, 1998 (Box 17)
      - Pis'mo Goratsiiu (Box 17)
      - Trudy i dni (Box 17)
    - Evtushenko, Evgenii, Ne umirai prezhde smerti, 1998 (Box 17)
    - Lemkhin, Mikhail, Joseph Brodsky: Leningrad Fragments, 1998 (Box 17)
    - Lincoln, W. Bruce, Between Heaven and Hell, 1998 (Box 17)
    - Volkov, Solomon, 1998 (Box 17)
      - Conversations With Joseph Brodsky (Box 17)
      - Dialogi s Iosifom Brodskom (Box 17)
    - Mac Fadeyn, David, Joseph Brodsky and the Baroque, 1998 (Box 18)
    - Volkov, Marina et al., Portrait of the Poet Joseph Brodsky, 1998 (Box 18)
    - Brodskii, Predstavlenie, 1999 (Box 18)
    - Brodsky, Joseph, Discovery, 1999 (Box 18)
    - Losev, Lev and Valentina Polukhina, Joseph Brodsky: The Art of a Poem, 1999 (Box 18)
    - Rigsbee, David, The Styles of Ruin: Joseph Brodsky and the Postmodernist Elegy, 1999 (Box 18)
    - Brodsky, Joseph, Collected Poems in English, 2000. (Box 18)
      Uncorrected proof
- Joseph Brosdky 2001 Increment File, 1973-2001. (Box 18)
  Correspondence, consisting of one letter, and printed matter, arranged chronologically by title
  - Correspondence. Letter from Joseph Brodsky to Ronald Steam, 1983 May 14 (Box 52)
  - Printed matter. Publications by or about Joseph Brodsky, 1973-2001.
    Brodsky's name is omitted where he is the author
    - Selected Poems, George L. Kline, trans., Middlesex, 1973 (Box 52)
    - V Anglii, Ann Arbor, 1977. (Box 52)
      Signed original of limited edition of poem. Use photocopy is provided
    - Less than One: Selected Essays, Middlesex, 1986 (Box 52)
    - Literary Review, 1986 January. (Box 53)
      Includes an interview with Brodsky, pp. 10-12
    - Dizdarevic, Zlatko, Sarajevo: A War Journal, New York, 1993. (Box 53)
      Includes a preface by Brodsky
    - Pochwala nudy, 1996. (Box 53)
      Polish translation of On Grief and Reason
    - Homage to Robert Frost, London, 1997. (Box 53)
      Includes essay by Brodsky
    - The Nobel Lecture and Acceptance, Milan, 1997 (Box 53)
    - Wiersze ostatnie, Krakow, 1998. (Box 53)
      Polish translation of So Forth
    - Heaney, Seamus, Audenesque, Paris, 1998 (Box 53)
    - Bol'shaia kniga interv'iu, Moscow, 2000 (Box 53)
    - Bol'shaia kniga interv'iu, revised edition, Moscow, 2000 (Box 53)
    - Gorbin, Iakov, ed., Iosif Brodskii i mir, Moscow, 2000 (Box 53)
    - Chast' rechi, New York, 2000 (Box 53)
    - Konets prekrasnoi epokhi, New York, 2000 (Box 53)
    - Novye stansy k avguste, New York, 2000 (Box 54)
    - Ostanovka v pustyne, New York, 2000 (Box 54)
    - Poklonit'sia teni, Saint Petersburg, 2000 (Box 54)
    - Sochineniia Iosifa Brodskogo, Saint Petersburg, 2000 (Box 54)
    - Uraniia, New York, 2000 (Box 54)
    - V ozhidanii barbarov, Saint Petersburg, 2000 (Box 54)
    - Shtern, Liudmila, Brodskii: Osia, Iosif, Joseph, Moscow, 2001 (Box 54)
    - Peremena Imperii, Moscow, 2001 (Box 54)
    - MacKinnon, Lachlan, "A Break from Dullness," Times Literary Supplement, 2001 June 22 (Box 54)
    - Letters to the editor, Times Literary Supplement, 2001 June-July. (Box 54)
      Printed copies of three letters concerning Brodsky
- Joseph Brodsky 2004 Increment File, 1979-2003.
  Printed matter, arranged chronologically by title, and photograph. Materials received in 2004
  - Printed matter. Publications by or about Brodsky. Brodsky's name is omitted where he is the author
    - Parts of Speech, New York, 1979. (Box-folder 157: 2)
      Sample pages submitted to publisher by printer
    - Naiman, Anatoli, Stikhotvoreniia Anatoliia Naimana, Tenafly, New Jersey, 1989. (Folder 157: 3)
      Afterword by Brodsky
    - Iosif Brodskii razmerom podlinnika, Talinn, 1990 (Folder 157: 4)
    - Korobova, Era, "Tozhdestvo drukh variantov: O grafike Iosifa Brodskogo," Russkaia mysl', 1991 December 6 (Folder 157: 5)
    - Isaac and Abraham, St. Petersburg, 1994. (Folder 157: 6)
      Illustrated with lithographs by M. Karasik
    - Azadovskii, K. M. (ed.), Iosif Brodskii, St. Petersburg, 1997 (Box-folder 158: 1)
    - Stizhevskaia, Natal'ia, Pis'mena perspektivy, Moscow, 1997 (Folder 158: 2)
    - Billington, James H., The Face of Russia, 1998 (Folder 158: 3)
    - Venezia per Brodskij: Nel 60o anniversario della nascita, 2000. (Folder 158: 4)
      Photocopy of festival program
    - Etkind, Efim, Zapiski nezagovorshchika. Barselonskaia proza, Saint Petersburg, 2001 (Folder 158: 5)
    - Nativity Poems, 2001
      - Galley proofs (Folder 158: 6)
      - Paperback edition (Box-folder 159: 1)
      - Hardback edition (Folder 159: 2)
    - Pis'ma rimskomu drugu, 2001 (Folder 159: 3)
    - Rein, Evgeny, Selected Poems, Tarset, England, 2001. (Folder 159: 4)
      Foreword by Brodsky
    - Shtern, Liudmila, Brodskii: Osia, Iosif, Joseph, Moscow, 2001 (Folder 159: 5)
    - Birkerts, Sven, My Sky Blue Trades, New York, 2002 (Folder 159: 6)
    - Madra-Shallcross, Božena, Through the Poet's Eye: The Travels of Zagajewski, Herbert, and Brodsky, Evanston, Illinois, 2002 (Box-folder 160: 1)
    - Verkheil, Keis, Tanets vokrug mira: Vstrechi s Iosifom Brodskim, Saint Petersburg, 2002 (Folder 160: 2)
    - George, Arthur L. with Elena George, St. Petersburg: Russia's Window to the Future—the First Three Centuries, New York, 2003 (Folder 160: 3)
    - Photograph, n.d. (Folder 160: 4)
      One print depicting Brodsky
- Boris Pasternak File, 1910-1998.
  Appraisals, bibliographies, correspondence, packing lists and receipts; biographical material re Boris Pasternak; correspondence and writings by Boris Pasternak; material related to academic conferences and exhibits about Pasternak; writings about Boris Pasternak; photographs; compact disks of readings by and about Boris Pasternak; videotapes, including of the motion picture "Doktor Zhivago," as well as the script and publicity related to the motion picture; posters; memorabilia, including a ceramic bust of Boris Pasternak, and printed matter, including books, scholarly journals, and popular magazines, arranged by physical form. The extensive printed matter, at the end of the series, consists of publications by and about Boris Pasternak, and is arranged chronologically by title or author, with the spellings conforming to those of the original publications. Transliterations are supplied for non-Russian alphabets. The original correspondence and writings are restricted, and use copies are available in Box 20
  - General
    - Bibliographies
      - Holtzman, Irwin, A Check List of Boris Leonidovich Pasternak Books in English, 1990. (Box-folder 19: 1)
        Printed copy
      - University libraries and the Library of Congress, 1996. (Folder 19: 2)
    - Catalog cards and packing lists for the Holtzman Collection, 1998 (Folder 19: 3)
    - Correspondence related to material in the Holtzman Collection
      - General, 1961 (Folder 19: 4)
      - Giangiacomo Feltrinelli Editore, 1958. (Folder 19: 5)
        Photocopies
      - Holtzman, Irwin, 1992-1997 (Folder 19: 6)
    - List of printed matter donated to the Pasternak museum at Peredelkino, 1990. (Folder 19: 7)
  - Biographical file. Press releases of the Soviet embassy in the U.S. re the publication of, Doctor Zhivago, including "Discussions of Pasternak's Doctor Zhivago," "Letter from Boris Pasternak to the Editors of Pravda," and "Letter to Boris Pasternak from the Editorial Board of Novyi Mir Magazine,", 1958 November 12 (Folder 19: 8)
  - Clippings, 1988-1997 (Folder 19: 9)
  - Conference file, 1990-1997
    - Akademiia Nauk, "Pasternak Centenary,", 1990
      - General (Folder 19: 10)
      - "Literaturno-muzykal'nyi kontsert..." Moscow, 1990. (Folder 19: 11)
    - Oxford University, "Boris Pasternak Centenary Conference,", 1990. (Folder 19: 12)
    - Philipps-Universität Marburg, 1991.; See also Exhibit file/Brüder Grimm-Museum (Folder 19: 13)
      Program.
    - Stanford University
      - "Boris Pasternak Centennial: An American-Soviet Conference,", 1990.; See also Exhibit file
        - Clippings (Folder 19: 14)
        - Correspondence of I. T. Holtzman, 1990 (Folder 19: 15)
        - Programs and schedules (Folder 19: 16)
        - Miscellany (Folder 19: 17)
      - "Poetry in Revolution: Boris Pasternak's My Sister, Life,", 1997. (Folder 19: 18)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1960. (Box 20)
    Photocopies. Originals in Restricted materials
    - Goyke (?), 1959 April 18 (Folder 20: 1)
    - Iliew, Ilko, 1959 November 11 (Folder 20: 2)
    - Ivinskaia, Olga, 1960. (Folder 20: 3)
      Unsigned note
    - Livanov Boris and Evgeniia, 1940 November 11, 1957 July 25, 1959 March 30, and undated note (Folder 20: 4)
    - Mathot, H. J., 1958 August 5 and December 23 (Folder 20: 5)
    - Sullivan, Ada Fleming, 1959 August 10 (Folder 20: 6)
    - Zhuravlev, Dmitrii, n.d. (Folder 20: 7)
      envelope
  - Exhibit file, 1984-1998
    - Brüder Grimm-Museum, Kassel, "Boris Pasternak und Deutschland,", 1992. (Folder 20: 8)
      Program and poster
    - Hebrew University of Jerusalem, "Boris Pasternak and His Times,", 1984. (Folder 20: 9)
    - Muzei A. A. Akhmatovoi, M. I. Tsvetaevoi, B. L. Pasternaka, Novosibirsk. Program and invitations for exhibit and benefit reading, 1989 (Folder 20: 10)
    - Russian State University of the Humanities, "The Life of Boris Pasternak's Doctor Zhivago,", 1998. (Folder 20: 11)
    - South Bank Centre, "An Exhibition Celebrating Boris Pasternak in His Centenary Year,", 1990. (Folder 20: 12)
    - Stanford University
      - "Boris Leonidovich Pasternak, 1890-1960: A Centennial Exhibition From the Private Collections of Irwin T. and Shirley Holtzman,", 1990.; See also Conference file and Photographs (Folder 20: 13)
        Captions, correspondence, and miscellany.
      - "Poetry and Revolution,", 1989. (Folder 20: 14)
        Catalog
    - University of Michigan, "Michigan Collects," 1989, and "A Day of Dedication/Display/Discussion: Boris Leonidovich Pasternak 1890-1960,", 1990.; See also Photographs (Folder 20: 15)
      Miscellany.
  - Writings, 1914-1959.; See also Printed matter (Boxes 27-48)
    Photocopies. Originals in Restricted materials.
    - Unidentified note, n.d. (Folder 20: 16)
    - Untitled group of poems, including "Belaia noch'," "Leto v gorode," "Avgust," "Kolybel'nye pesni," "Bessonnitsa," "Khmel'," "Pod otkrytym nebom,", n.d. (Folder 20: 17)
    - "Neskol'ko stikhotvorenii,", n.d. (Folder 20: 18)
    - Bliznets v tuchakh, Lirika, Moscow, 1914. (Folder 20: 19)
      Handmade copy
    - Avtografy, 1917? (Folder 20: 20)
      Moscow? Printed copy
    - Untitled group of poems, 1947, inscribed, "Dorogoi Zhenichke Livanovoi." (Folder 20: 21)
    - Untitled handmade book of poetry. Inscribed for C. M. Bowra, 1948. (Folder 20: 22)
    - "Dopolnenie k sborniku Kogda razguliaetsia,", 1958-1959. (Folder 20: 23)
  - Writings by others, 1984-1990
    - Fleishman, Lazar
      - Correspondence with Elena and Evgenii Pasternak, 1985 (Folder 20: 24)
      - Writings
        - "Unknown Autographs in the I. T. Holtzman Collection,", n.d. (Folder 20: 25)
        - Boris Pasternak v tridtsatye gody, 1984. (Folder 20: 26-27)
          Page proof
        - Boris Pasternak, 1989.
    - Livanov, Vasilii, "Beyond Fiction, Reminiscences and Impressions about Boris Pasternak," F. Ournov, trans., 1990. (Box-folder 21: 1)
    - Navrozov, Andrei
      - Correspondence with Peter Owen, 1989-1990. (Folder 21: 2)
        Includes letter of Ann Pasternak Slater
      - Writings, Second Nature: Forty Six Poems by Boris Pasternak, 1987-1989. (Folder 21: 3-7)
        Uncorrected proofs
    - Ozerov, Lev, 1990. (Folder 21: 8)
      Typescript. Includes clippings
    - Proffer, Ellendea, "Four Letters of Boris Pasternak," (Folder 21: 9)
    - Urnov, Dmitrii, "Bezumnoe prevyshenie svoikh sil," Novyi mir, nos. 1-4, 1988. (Folder 21: 10)
      Typescript drafts
  - Restricted materials, 1914-1960 (Box 22)
    - Correspondence., See Box 20 for use copies
      - Goyke (?), 1959 April 18 (Folder 22: 1)
      - Iliew, Ilko, 1959 November 11 (Folder 22: 2)
      - Ivinskaia, Olga, 1960. (Folder 22: 3)
      - Livanov Boris and Evgeniia, 1940 November 11, 1957 July 25, 1959 March 30, and undated note (Folder 22: 4)
      - Mathot, H. J., 1958 August 5 and December 23 (Folder 22: 5)
      - Sullivan, Ada Fleming, 1959 August 10 (Folder 22: 6)
      - Zhuravlev, Dmitrii, n.d. (Folder 22: 7)
    - Writings., See Box 20 for use copies
      - Unidentified note, n.d. (Folder 22: 8)
      - Untitled group of poems, including "Belaia noch'," "Leto v gorode," "Avgust," "Kolybel'nye pesni," "Bessonnitsa," "Khmel'," "Pod otkrytym nebom,", n.d. (Folder 22: 9)
      - "Neskol'ko stikhotvorenii,", n.d. (Folder 22: 10)
      - Bliznets v tuchakh, Lirika, Moscow, 1914. (Folder 22: 11)
      - Avtografy, 1917? (Folder 22: 12)
      - Untitled group of poems, 1947. (Folder 22: 13)
        Inscribed, "Dorogoi Zhenichke Livanovoi." Typescript
      - Untitled handmade book of poetry. Inscribed for C. M. Bowra, 1948. (Folder 22: 14)
      - "Dopolnenie k sborniku Kogda razguliaetsia,", 1958-1959. (Folder 22: 15)
    - Photographs
      - 1 print depicting Boris Pasternak, n.d. (Folder 22: 16)
        Inscribed for the Livanovs
      - 1 print depicting Boris Pasternak at Peredelkino, April 4, 1959. (Folder 22: 17)
        Includes inscription for Rev. Cornelius Greenway
  - Photographs (Box 23)
    - 32 prints depicting Boris Pasternak, 1910(?)-1960 (Folder 23: 1)
    - 5 prints depicting Boris Pasternak at Peredelkino, 1957 (Folder 23: 2)
    - 5 prints depicting Boris Pasternak's funeral, 1960 (Folder 23: 3)
    - 18 prints depicting Boris Pasternak from the album Boris Pasternak: 1890-1960, 1990, and 5 postcards depicting Boris Pasternak (Folder 23: 4)
    - Proof sheet with 4 prints depicting Boris Pasternak in the 1920's (Folder 23: 5)
    - 56 prints related to Irwin T. Holtzman's visits to the Soviet Union, 1984-1990 (Folder 23: 6)
    - 11 prints related to the exhibits at the University of Michigan, 1989-1990 (Folder 23: 7)
    - 5 prints related to the exhibit at Stanford University, 1990 (Folder 23: 8)
    - 7 prints and 6 slides from the brochure Doctor Zhivago: Thirtieth Anniversary, 1996 (Folder 23: 9)
    - 1 print depicting Marina Tsvetaeva, n.d. (Folder 23: 10)
    - 20 negatives depicting Boris Pasternak, 1910(?)-1960 (Folder 23: 11)
  - Audio-visual file., See also Oversize file/Phonorecords (Box 24)
    - Compact disks
      - "Poets and Painters as Composers," FSM, 1980 (Box 24)
      - "Polnoe sobranie zvukozapisei avtorskogo chteniia," Dom-Muzei Borisa Pasternaka, 1996 (Box 24)
    - Phonotape cassettes
      - Pasternak, Boris, "Chitaet avtor,", n.d. (Box 24)
      - Pasternak, E. B., "J. P. Obituary,", 1993 (Box 24)
      - Scofield, Paul, "Paul Scofield Reads Doctor Zhivago,", 1979 (Box 24)
    - Videotapes
      - "Doctor Zhivago,", 1965 (Box 24)
      - Interview with J. Pasternak, 1986 (Box 24)
      - "Pasternak Gala: Bolshoi Theatre, Moscow,", 1990 (Box 24)
  - Oversize file (Box 25)
    - Phonorecords
      - "Golosa zazvuchali vnov',", n.d. (Box 25)
      - "Pasternak Speaks,", n.d. (Box 25)
      - "Pasternak: Spoken Arts," Spoken Arts Inc., n.d. (Box 25)
      - "Doctor Zhivago: The Original Sound Track Album,", 1965 (Box 25)
      - "William Shakespeare: Chitaiut avtory perevodov,", 1976 (Box 25)
      - "Stranitsy russkoi poezii," Melodia, 1982 (Box 25)
      - "Taina remesla," Melodia, 1983 (Box 25)
      - "Boris Pasternak: Chitaet avtor," Firma Melodia, 1989 (Box 25)
    - Posters (Box 25)
      - "Doctor Zhivago," motion picture advertisements, 1965 (Box 25)
        - English (Box 25)
        - German (Box 25)
      - "Vek Pasternaka," Voznesenskii, A., 1990 (Box 25)
    - Press release from producers of the motion picture "Doctor Zhivago,", 1965 (Box 25)
    - Writings. Pasternak, Boris, My Sister – Life, Mark Rudman, trans., Yuri Kuper illustrator, The Limited Editions Club, 1992 (Box 25)
  - Memorabilia, n.d. (Box 26)
    - Bottle, "Zhivago Vodka" (Box 26)
    - Bust of Boris Pasternak, signed C. R. C. (Box 26)
  - Printed matter. Publications by and about Boris Pasternak, arranged chronologically. Boris Pasternak's name is omitted when he is the author. Hardback, unless otherwise indicated (Box 27)
    - General
      - Poetry: Shelley's Poems, Everyman's Library, 1910. (Box 27)
        Inscribed by Boris Pasternak for Eugenie Livanoff, 1946
      - Lirika: Pervyii Al'manakh, Moscow, 1913. (Box 27)
        Inscribed by contributing poets, including Boris Pasternak
      - Bliznets v tuchakh, Lirika, Moscow, 1914 (Box 27)
      - Rukonog, Tsentrifuga, Moscow, 1914 (Box 27)
      - Vesennee kontragentstvo muz, D. Burliuk and S. Vermel', eds., 1915 (Box 27)
      - Poverkh bar'erov, Tsentrifuga, Moscow, 1917 (Box 27)
      - Iav': Stikhi, 1919 (Box 27)
      - Liren', Liren', 1920 (Box 27)
      - My, Knigoizdatel'stvo Pri Vserossiiskom Soiuze Poetov Chihi-Pikhi, Moscow, 1920 (Box 27)
      - Annenkov, Iurii, Portrety, Petropolis, 1922. (Box 27)
        Reprint
      - Ehrenburg, Il'ia, Portrety russkikh poetov, Berlin, 1922 (Box 27)
      - Sestra moia zhizn', Izdatel'stvo Z. I. Grzhebina, Moscow. Two copies, 1922 and 1923 (Box 27)
      - LEF: Zhurnal levogo fronta No. 1, V. V. Maiakovskii, ed., Moscow-Petrograd, 1923 (Box 27)
      - Temy i var'iatsii, Gelikon, 1923. (Box 27)
        Two copies
      - Rasskazy, Krug, Moscow-Leningrad, 1925 (Box 27)
      - Izbrannye stikhi, Izdatel'stvo Uzel, Moscow, 1926 (Box 27)
      - Karusel', Gosudarstvennoe Izdatel'stvo, Leningrad, 1926 (Box 27)
      - Deviat'sot piatyii god, Gosudarstvennoe Izdatel'stvo, Moscow-Leningrad, 1927 (Box 27)
      - Dve knigi: Stikhi, Gosudarstvennoe Izdatel'stvo, Moscow-Leningrad, 1927. (Box 27)
        Inscribed by author
      - Izbrannye stikhi, Biblioteka Ogonek, 1929 (Box 27)
      - Poverkh bar'erov, Gosudarstvennoe Izdatel'stvo, Moscow-Leningrad, 1929. (Box 27)
        Inscribed O. Ivinskaia
      - Zverinets, Gosudarstvennoe Izdatel'stvo, Moscow, 1929 (Box 27)
      - Deviat'sot piatyi god, Gosudarstvennoe Izdatel'stvo, 1930 (Box 27)
      - Dve knigi: Stikhi, Gosudarstvennoe Izdatel'stvo, 1930. (Box 27)
      - This Quarter, 1930 July-August (Box 27)
      - Okhrannaia gramota, Izdatel'stvo Pisatelei Leningrada, 1931. (Box 27)
      - Poverkh bar'erov: Stikhi raznykh let, Gosudarstvennoe Izdatel'stvo, Khudozhestvennoi Literatury, 1931 (Box 27)
      - Spektorskii, Gosudarstvennoe Izdatel'stvo Khudozhestvennoi Literatury, Moscow-Leningrad, 1931 (Box 27)
      - The New Review, Winter 1931-1932 (Box 27)
      - Deviat'sot piatyi god, Izdatel'stvo Pisatelei Leningrada, 1932 (Box 27)
      - Vtoroe rozhdenie, Federatsiia, 1932 (Box 27)
      - Izbrannye stikhi, Sovetskaia Literatura, 1933. (Box 28)
        Two copies, one with inscription by author for Anna Akhmatova (forgery)
      - Poemy, Sovetskaia Literatura, 1933 (Box 28)
      - Slonim, Mark, Portrety sovetskikh pisatelei, Parabola, Paris, 1933 (Box 28)
      - Stikhotvoreniia v odnom tome, Izdatel'stvo Pisatelei v Leningrade, 1933 (Box 28)
      - Literaturnaia Entsiklopediia, vol. 8, Sovetskaia Entsiklopediia, Moscow, 1934 (Box 28)
      - Povest', Izdatel'stvo Pisatelei v Leningrade, 1934. (Box 28)
        From the library of Aleksandr Pasternak
      - Soviet Literature, George Reavey and Mark Slonim, eds., 1934 (Box 28)
      - Soviet Literature: An Anthology, George Reavey and Mark Slonim, eds., 1934 (Box 28)
      - Vtoroe rozhdenie, Sovetskii Pisatel', 1934 (Box 28)
      - Gruzinskie liriki, Sovetskii Pisatel', 1935 (Box 28)
      - Stikhotvoreniia v odnom tome, Khudozhestvennaia Literatura, 1935 and 1936 (Box 28)
      - 1905: Leitenant Shmidt, Khudozhestvennaia Literatura, Moscow, 1937 (Box 28)
      - Gruzinskie liriki, SP, 1937 (Box 28)
      - Jewish Short Stories of Today, Morris Kreitman, ed., 1937 (Box 28)
      - Left Review, 1937 November (Box 28)
      - Jewish Short Stories of To-Day, Morris Kreitman, ed., 1938 (Box 28)
      - Bol'shaia Sovetskaia Entsyklopediia, vol. 43, Sovetskaia Entsiklopediia, 1939 (Box 28)
      - Aseev, N., Maiakovskii nachinaetsia, Sovetskiii Pisatel', 1940 (Box 28)
      - Izbrannye perevody, Sovetskiii Pisatel', 1940 (Box 28)
      - Gamlet: Prints datskii, translation of William Shakespeare's Hamlet, Goslitizdat, 1941 (Box 28)
      - Modern Poems from Russia, Gerard Shelley, trans., George Allen and Unwin, 1942 (Box 28)
      - A Book of Russian Verse, C. M. Bowra, ed., 1943 (Box 28)
      - Kaun, Alexander, Soviet Poets and Poetry, University of California Press, 1943 (Box 28)
      - Na rannikh poezdakh: Novye stikhotvoreniia, Sovetskiii Pisatel', 1943. (Box 28)
        Two copies, one inscribed and signed for Boris Livanov, 1943, the other for George Reavey, 1944
      - Romeo i Dzhulietta, translation of William Shakespeare's Romeo and Juliet, OGIZ, 1944 (Box 28)
      - Boris Pasternak: The Collected Prose Works, Stefan Schimanski, ed., Lindsay Drummond, Ltd., London, 1945 (Box 29)
      - Izbrannye stikhi i poemy, OGIZ, 1945 (Box 29)
      - Otello venetsianskii mavr translation of William Shakespeare's Othello, OGIZ, 1945 (Box 29)
      - Zemnoi prostor: Stikhi, Sovetskii Pisatel', 1945. (Box 29)
        Two copies, one inscribed for George Reavey
      - Arkhangel'skii, A., Izbrannoe, OGIZ, 1946 (Box 29)